<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Thet Naing</title><link>https://naingthet.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Thet Naing</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://naingthet.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Credit Card Fraud Detection</title><link>https://naingthet.github.io/posts/fraud/fraud/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naingthet.github.io/posts/fraud/fraud/</guid><description>Project GitHub Repository
Introduction In this project, we will develop classification systems for the detection of fraudulent credit card activity, using a dataset of credit card transactions provided on Kaggle. As most credit card transactions are genuine, this task will require us to work with a highly imbalanced dataset. Thus, to build a powerful classifier that is capable of detecting fraud, we will need to solve the issue of data imbalance, which will be a key consideration throughout this project.</description></item><item><title>House Prices - Advanced Regression Techniques</title><link>https://naingthet.github.io/posts/house-prices/house-prices/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naingthet.github.io/posts/house-prices/house-prices/</guid><description>Project GitHub Repository
Introduction In this project, we will tackle the Kaggle House Prices: Advanced Regression Techniques competition. The goal of this project is to develop a robust and powerful regression model to predict house sale prices given 79 features describing homes in Ames, Iowa. The objective is to achieve the highest validation accuracy possible, without peeking at the test data or allowing the test data to influence our methodology.</description></item><item><title>Analyzing Donald Trump's Tweets Using Natural Language Processing</title><link>https://naingthet.github.io/posts/trump/trump/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naingthet.github.io/posts/trump/trump/</guid><description>Project GitHub Repository
Introduction There is no doubt that Donald Trump has been a very controversial and polarizing figure in the United States, especially since he announced his run for the presidency in 2015.
Throughout his presidency, Donald Trump has used Twitter as a powerful tool to reach his supporters. The social media service has, without a doubt, been one of his most powerful tools.
This project was primarily inspired by Donald Trump&amp;rsquo;s relentless use of Twitter, as it has raised some important questions, including but not limited to:</description></item><item><title>Classifying Optic Neuropathies with Random Forest</title><link>https://naingthet.github.io/posts/optic-neuropathy/optic-neuropathy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://naingthet.github.io/posts/optic-neuropathy/optic-neuropathy/</guid><description>Project GitHub Repository
Preface This post and accompanying GitHub repository present the abstract and full manuscript for my undergraduate research on the applications of machine learning algorithms to the classification of optic neuropathies. In this research, multiple blinded and experienced observers measured key morphological features of the retina from optical coherence tomography (OCT) scans. These metrics were then used as the features on which the models were trained. The goal of this experiment was to develop robust models that could accurately distinguish between eyes from three groups of participants: patients with non-arteritic ischemic optic neuropathy (NAION), open-angle glaucoma (OAG), and healthy controls.</description></item></channel></rss>